<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="stats">
  <title>Webcampak Statistics</title>

  <para>Webcampak is equipped with sensors collecting statistics about
  internal system at regular interval. Those statistics have been created to
  let you see, quickly, if Webcampak and its sources are operating as
  expected. </para>

  <screenshot>
    <screeninfo>Webcampak menu</screeninfo>

    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.stats.menu.en.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>

  <section>
    <title>Number of pictures per source and per day</title>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>Number of pictures per sources and per day</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.stats.nbpictures.en.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <para>You can use this window to check if capture were stable for a
    particular source. If you move your mouse over a specific day, the number
    of pictures captured during this day will be displayed.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Pictures size per source and per day</title>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>Pictures size per source and per day</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.stats.picsize.en.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <para>You can use this window to chek disk usage for each day of capture
    for a particular source.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Source disk usage evolution per day</title>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>Source disk usage evolution</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.stats.sourcesize.en.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <para>This window display disk usage evolution of a source over time. You
    can see both picture usage and video usage on this graph, with pictures in
    green and videos in blue. Global usage corresponds to the top of the blue
    line (here around 8GB).</para>

    <para>If you click on the legend you can display only pictures, only
    videos or both. </para>

    <para>The above capture is very interesting, as you can see automated
    picture deletion is activated and only 8 days of capture are kept by the
    system. You can see a disk usage increase during the day, with old
    pictures being deleted each morning, corresponding to the drop you can see
    on the graph.</para>

    <para>As you can see, disk usage always remains around 8GB.</para>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>Disk usage per day (with no automated deletion)</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.stats.sourcesize2.fr.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <para>The above graph is the most usual scenario, with disk usage
    constantly increasing as time pass by, on this graph you can see disk
    usage going from 48GB to 54GB in around 10 days.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>System statitics</title>

    <para>Note: this window is only available to Webcampak and Webcampak Cloud
    Max users.</para>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>System Statistics</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.stats.system.en.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <para>This window gives general system details, such as bandwidth, memory,
    hard disk, CPU usages.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
