<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="system">
  <title>System configuration</title>

  <para>This window can be used to configure Webcampak system settings.
  Usually those settings are confgured once for all and never modified during
  the product lifetime.</para>

  <section>
    <title>Webcampak system settings</title>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>Webcampak system settings</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.general.general.en.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>

    <section>
      <title>Network</title>

      <para>Inidicate the name of your main network interface, this is used to
      generate system stats.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Timezone</title>

      <para>Timezone where your Webcampak is physically located.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Gphoto</title>

      <para>Webcampak configuration in a multi-camera setup is a complex
      implementation and is only compatible with some DSLR cameras.</para>

      <para>Activate this module if you connect multiple DSLR cameras via USB
      to Webcampak. Then indicate if those cameras are identical (same brand
      &amp; model) or different.</para>

      <para>Webcampak must be able to understand how to assign a camera to a
      source and ensure this configuration is maintained whatever happens
      (camera reboot, webcampak reboot, ...).</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Global FTP account (resources)</title>

      <para>As mentioned previously, each source get assigned a dedicated FTP
      account. This "wpresources" account is a global account that can be used
      to access Webcampak system-wide resources (excluding sources
      content).</para>

      <para>When you log in you will have access to: </para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Logs from various sources</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>audio directory to upload MP3 files, those files will be
          available to all sources</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>watermark directory, those files will be available to all
          sources</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>cache directory, containing temporary files. You can delete
          all files within this directory in case of major issue.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Statistics</title>

      <para>This module is used by Webcampak team to estimate how often our
      product is being used. Thanks for participating.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Phidget</title>

      <para>Select this box if a Phidget board is connected to
      Webcampak</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Email configuration</title>

    <para>This tab can be used to configured how Webcampak is going to send
    email (outgoing SMTP server).</para>

    <screenshot>
      <screeninfo>Global email configuration</screeninfo>

      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="http://doc.webcampak.com/screenshots/wpak2.general.email.en.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>
  </section>
</chapter>
