<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
	"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">  
   <chapter id="overview">
    <title>Overview</title>

    <section>
      <title>Audience</title>

      <para>Welcome to this Webcampak user guide.</para>

      <para>This document has been created to detail Webcampak and contains
      details about all functionalities available.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>What is Webcampak ?</title>

      <para>Webcampak is a device aimed to automatically capture, store and
      process pictures initially created to be used with DSLR cameras.</para>

      <para>Our product has evolved and is compatible with a wide range of
      devices:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>DSLR and point-and-shoot cameras</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>USB webcams</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Web pictures</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>IP cameras / Webcampak</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Streaming sources</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Being compatible with high-end DSLR cameras, Webcampak can process
      very high quality pictures when connected to an appropriate camera (not
      all DSLR are compatible).</para>

      <para>Canon point-and-shoot cameras, sold after 2009, are not compatible
      anymore but you can still find such camera on the second-hand market for
      a fraction of their original price.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Communication</title>

        <para>Webcampak has been conceived right from the beginning to be
        network-enabled. It is compatible with various types of links:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>GPRS/3G/4G</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Wi-Fi (2,4 or 5 Ghz)</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Ethernet</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Satellite</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Some Internet links (especially wireless) are subject to FUP
        (Fair Use Policy) limiting the amount of data to be transmitted each
        month. Webcampak can fit almost any FUP limitations by:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Sending a fraction of captured pictures (for example, send 1
            out of 5 pictures)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Reducing pictures resolution of pictures sent over
            network</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Cropping pictures</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>By adjusting those parameters you can limit the amount of data
        to be transferred and therefore be compliant with your provider's
        FUP.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Picture quality</title>

        <para>Webcampak compatible with all Canon DSLR cameras and associated
        lenses.</para>

        <para>Picture quality during day or night time will be very close (if
        not identical) to quality that can be obtained by a professional
        photographer for a single shot.</para>

        <para>Take in consideration that some cameras and/or lenses might
        required Webcampak adjustments (might require a larger enclosure due
        to lens size).</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Webcampak versions</title>

        <para>There is only one Webcampak solution, but our product is
        available in two different models:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Webcampak: is an automated capture device in an all-weather
            enclosure. </para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Webcampak-Pro: is a concentration point for pictures, it can
            process a potentially unlimited number of sources. It has been
            created to be installed in an IT room or a datacenter.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>Both models are equipped with the exact same software, the only
        difference being physical elements (all-weather enclosure, amount of
        RAM, CPU, ...).</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Where to procure Webcampak ?</title>

        <para>Webcampak is available for sale or for rent in any country.
        Webcampak is always provide pre-configured and ready to use. It can
        also be provided with a wide range of services.</para>

        <para>We have a "service approach", before providing you with a
        quotation we will study your requirements in detail and find the best
        way to answer those. Webcampak is not a static product, it can be
        adapted to a potentially unlimited number of scenarios.</para>

        <para>We would be happy to have a chat with you regarding your
        project:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>by phone: +33 (0)2 51 10 74 15</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>by email: contact-at-webcampak.com (replace -at- by
            @)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>We can answer in French, English and German.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Features</title>

      <para>We are constantly adding new features to Webcampak, the list below
      might not be exhaustive.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Features list</title>

        <section>
          <title>Picture capture</title>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Capture sources</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>PTP cameras (point-and-shoot and DSLR)</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>USB webcams</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>IP cameras (via FTP, HTTP, RTSP)</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Web pictures (via HTTP, FTP)</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>other Webcampak</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Filename with capture date</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Support multiple capture sources per Webcampak</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Automated capture</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Every X seconds/minutes</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Specific timeframe (for example between 6:00 am and
                  4:00 pm)</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Specific days (for example Monday and Friday, Tuesday
                  to Saturday, ...)</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Pictures manipulations</title>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Crop picture: size and location</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Add legend: choose font, size, color, shadow,
              location</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Add watermark: choose location and transparency</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Add a logo or mask on your picture</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Obstruct some areas</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Add weather sensor: size and location</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Resize picture</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Create thumbnails</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Timelapse videos</title>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Automated (every day)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Custom (user-specified interval)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Pre-process picture and batch manipulations</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Video effect (Tiltshift, Charcoal, Colorin,
                  ...)</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Add legend</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Add watermark</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Resize</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Zoom</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Crop</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Traveling / panning effect</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Filter similar pictures</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Add an audio track (mp3 file or playlist)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Multiple H.264 video formats H.264 (1080p, 720p, 480p,
              custom), FPS</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Create MP4 file for in-browser display</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Send pictures and videos</title>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Send pictures to remote FTP server (2 servers per
              picture)</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Send thumbnails/hotlinks to remote FTP server</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Send videos to remote FTP server</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Send hotlink videos to remote FTP server</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Upload videos to Youtube</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Remote access</title>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Authenticated web interface (HTTP)</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Administration panel</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Viewer panel</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Pictures and videos reachable via FTP</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>VPN compatible (OpenVPN)</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>System management</title>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Storage space management:</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Delete pictures automatically after a user-specified
                  number of days</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Delete pictures automatically if overall picture size
                  over XXX MB (user specified)</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Emails:</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Send an email in case of multiple capture
                  errors</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Send an email when capture is back</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Send an email once custom video creation is
                  completed</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Phidget board</para>

              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Restart camera automatically after multiple capture
                  failures</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Store sensor measurements</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Create daily graphs</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                  <para>Display capture progress on LCD screen</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>New features</title>

        <para>We listen to our customers, users and prospects. </para>

        <para>If for any reason Webcampak do not answer your requirement or if
        you believe an additional feature might be interesting, just let us
        know. We will study how to modify Webcampak to fulfill this
        requirement, either by updating the software or implementing a third
        party solution.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Sources</title>

      <para>Webcampak core is associated to the concept of "sources", giving
      it adaptability and scalability.</para>

      <para>A Webcampak source is a configuration process aimed to capture and
      process pictures. A source is not necessarily attached to a capture
      device (such as a camera), the capture can come from another Webcampak
      or another source from the same Webcampak.</para>

      <para>It allows sources to be cascaded and to potentially modify one
      single picture an unlimited number of times.</para>

      <para>Let's take a real world example:</para>

      <para>At a building site, the building company would like to generate a
      timelapse video of the whole construction project and at the same time,
      publish real-time pictures on its website to show building progress to
      its customers.</para>

      <para>Those two requirements need different pictures:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>For a timelapse video, pictures must be stored in the highest
          quality with a limited number of manipulations (no legend, no
          watermark, ...).</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>For real-time picture web-publishing, the construction company
          would like pictures to include the company's logo and a capture
          date.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>Therefore Webcampak has to process pictures differently, this can
      be done by cascading sources.</para>

      <para>A first source will capture the picture from the camera and store
      it for the timelapse video. This source will also send pictures to a
      second source. This second source will process the picture, insert a
      logo, date, resize it and send it to the company's website.</para>

      <para>All of this is done automatically by Webcampak with no human
      action past the initial configuration.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Files</title>

      <para>Your Webcampak will probably have to store a (very) large number
      of pictures. It has been designed for this task and multiple features
      are available to manage and secure those files.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Redundancy</title>

        <para>Always keep in mind that hardware failure or human error (i.e.
        delete pictures by mistake) can happen and it's always better to take
        precautions before such events happen.</para>

        <para>Webcampak is able to send pictures to remote FTP server, you can
        also store pictures automatically to another source of the same
        Webcampak to prevent human errors (just take in consideration that it
        will require twice the amount of disk space).</para>

        <para>Other mechanisms are available using third party products, we
        will study those with you based upon your requirements.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>Automated deletion</title>

        <para>Webcampak is equipped with automated deletion mechanisms to
        ensure its internal hard disk never runs out of space. Those
        mechanisms can be configured to fit various requirements. </para>

        <para>When Webcampak store its pictures to a remote server, it can use
        its internal disk space as a buffer to ensure no pictures are lost in
        case of network issue. Depending of the capture frequency and picture
        size, this buffer size can cover multiple days, even months.</para>
      </section>

      <section>
        <title>File structure</title>

        <para>Webcampak is equipped with multiple directory structures.</para>

        <section>
          <title>Global FTP account</title>

          <para>A global FTP account, shared with between sources will let you
          access:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>/audio/ : directory for mp3 and/or m3u files, used to add
              an audio track to your videos.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/cache/ : directory with temporary files, all files in
              this directory can be deleted in case of issue.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/logs/ : directory hosting system's logs for all
              sources.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/watermark/ : directory for watermark files to be added to
              pictures and/or videos.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Per-source FTP account</title>

          <para>Each source has its own FTP account, with the following
          directory structure:</para>

          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>/live/ : directory hosting hotlink pictures and
              videos.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/pictures/ : directory hosting pictures.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/pictures/20120423/ : pictures of the 23rd April
              2012.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/pictures/process-video/ : temporary directory, deleted
              automatically when a new video is created.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/pictures/process-videocustom/: temporary directory,
              deleted automatically when a new custom video is created.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/pictures/process-videopost/ : temporary directory,
              deleted automatically when a new post-prod. video process is
              initiated.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/tmp/ : pictures coming from IP cameras or other Webcampak
              must be uploaded to this directory to be processed by
              Webcampak.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>/videos/ : directory hosting videos.</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>

